This is a state diagram, and we need to turn
it into a flat state diagram.
Solving task one can help you solve this task.
The first state we have is F. Because if you
look at this diagram, if you go from the outside,
this is the only entrance, it takes us here
to this composite state.
And in this composite state, the only entrance
here is to go to F. Now, if we are in F, if
you are visiting F, then we have the possibility
to go from F to G and go back using A. So,
we just do that here.
From G, you can go with H and it takes you
to E, let's just add it here.
From E, you will go with K and K points at
this composite state as a whole.
And this composite state starts with F. So,
basically we're going from E to F using K,
let’s add it here.
And from E, you go with H. H points at D explicitly,
and D is a part of this composite state.
And this leads to visiting A and D at the
same time.
Let's add this here, we add one state, which
is called A and D. And when you are in A and
D at the same time, and you do A, it keeps
you in D but it moves you from A to B, this
means we go to a new state called B and D.
And we can go back from B and D. Because when
you are in B and D, there is this arrow with
A and it takes you back to AD, it doesn't
change anything with D, it just takes you
back from B to A and D stays visited.
And now while we are in A and D at the same
time, if we do B we have the similar case
as here.
Doing B takes us from D to C and it keeps
A visited.
This means we go to a state called A and C.
When you are in A and C at the same time.
And you do A it takes you to B but it keeps
you in C. So, you go to a new state called
B and C. And also you can go back from B and
C to A and C. And again you can go back from
A and C to A and D, and now look at this state
and this state.
We have B and C, B and D. And between C and
D, you can go back and forth with B, let's
add this here.
And since when you are in A or B or C or D
or any combinations of these, then this big
composite state is also considered active
and visited.
Then you can go with K, it takes you to this
composite state, which starts with F. So,
this means from either of these four, you
can go with K and it's going to take you to
the first state of this composite state which
is F. So, I just added four arrows from each
of these states with K and it takes you to
F. And now since we have covered everything
we can safely say we have created a corresponding
equivalent flat state diagram to the original
one.
It has no regions it has no hierarchical structure,
and at the same time is equivalent.